David Lee

10251 Hartshill Ln Sappington, MO, 63128 (314) 277-6084

 $\underline{stlpm4\,@\,yahoo.com}$

https://stlpm4.github.io/david-lee/

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Skilled DevOps professional with 12+ years of experience and a proven knowledge of advanced technology, application development, and emerging technologies. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the Senior Software Engineer role at your company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AT&T Senior Software Engineer Saint Louis, MO Jun 2007 - Present

Development Lead, Common Provisioning Services is responsible for provisioning network based and integrated offer solutions for consumer and enterprises through exposing REST based microservices to orchestrate provisioning of AT&T products, solutions, and offers directly to the network.

Key Accomplishments

- Designed and developed chatbot microservice using adaptive card technology. API would potentially save 3 minutes for every call in the call centers. Potential savings of 50k month for the company.
- Designed and developed FIRSTNET microservice to provision emergency responders on the network with SLA of 1000 transactions per 2 secs.
- Designed and developed ATT collaborate microservice for enhance mobile customers. The microservice handled average 60k transactions per day generating revenue of \$100k per month.
- Develop Restful microservices using emerging technology such as restlet, docker, springboot framework, Kubernetes on CI/CD pipeline.
- Created framework to develop non modeled restful microservices for the team. Framework reduced development effort in half, so they could spend more time on the business solutions.
- Developed microservices using TDD/BDD.
- Coordinate the design and implementation of various applications with its stakeholders; project managers, client representative, and development teams.
- Provide mentoring services to junior developers.
- Responsible for creating developers guide/technical how-to documentation to develop and deploy microservices
- Built and deployed docker containers on Kubernetes to break up monolithic legacy applications into microservices, improving developer's workflow, increasing scalability, and time to market.
- Daily use of agile development methodologies.

Developer, CSI Gateway responsible for single entry point into multiple middleware applications. Key Accomplishments

- Responsible for upgrading legacy CSI gateway onto spring boot framework, docker, Kubernetes architecture to increase scalability, and speed up deployment.
- Design and development quota management in the new gateway. This provided ability to block transactions if the user exceeded their usage limit.
- Upgrading logging from log4j to slf4j.
- Implement code changes, test code changes, and document code changes

Developer, Network Management in Common Services Integration, managed suite of services provided functionality for the inquiry, update, negotiating, and provisioning of UVERSE orders. Responsible for design, develop, and deploy M2E webservices and provide 24X7 support to internal as well as external customers. Key Accomplishments

- Design and Developed process models using business process modeling notation (business studio) and implemented SOA services using Model Driven Architecture for critical API initiatives.
- Responsible for ongoing projects to adapting to Agile methodology and Cloud service enablement.

- Troubleshoot and resolved connectivity issue such as jms, http, fusion with backends, upstream, and downstream.
- Developed interface definition schemas, map transformations, and code to translate public to private messaging.
- Developed XML schemas and XML mappings to handle public/private message translation.
- Created data and business rules using Contivo Analyst and java to perform data transformation between clients and backend systems.
- Interfaces with both clients and backends systems gathering system requirements and interface specifications.

Developer, Availability and Product Management Applications for Middleware Integration Services, managed suite of services providing functionality to retrieve, add, delete, and update identifiers information. Responsible for design, developer, and deploy EJB middleware services.

Key Accomplishments

- Coded new EJB methods and updated code to support ongoing releases.
- Designed, developed, deployed, and tested middleware services.
- Troubleshoot and resolved connectivity issues with backends, upstream, and downstream BIS applications.

Barnes Jewish Hospital

Saint Louis, MO

Registered Respiratory Therapist

Jan 1999 - May 2007

- Educate patients and their families about their conditions and teach appropriate disease management techniques, such as breathing exercises or the use of medications or respiratory equipment
- Troubleshoot and resolve software used for patient charting.
- Monitor patient's physiological responses to therapy, such as vital signs, arterial blood gases, or blood chemistry changes, and consult with physician if adverse reactions occur.
- Work as part of a team of physicians, nurses, or other healthcare professionals to manage patient care by assisting with medical procedures or related duties.

UNITED STATES ARMY

Tacoma, WA

Combat Medical Specialist Sergeant

Aug 1993 – Aug 1998

• Promoted to Platoon Sergeant fastest in my division based on my leadership abilities, training abilities, and motivating others. Supervised, trained, and counseled 16 active duty personnel

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY MISSOURI SAINT LOUIS

Saint Louis, MO

B.S. Computer Science (May 2007)

WEST KENTUCKY COMMUNITY AND TECHNICAL COLLEGE

Paducah, KY

A.S. Respiratory Therapy (May 1999)

SKILLS

MuleSoft, Java/J2EE, docker, Java script, Kubernetes, CICD, micro services, C, C++, SOA, Web Services, Eclipse, Unix/Linux, XML/XSD/XSLT, CVS/SVN, GIT, Maven, Ant, Hudson, TIBCO Business Studio, TIBCO Designer, Contivo, Nodejs, web development, java script, CSS, Microsoft Azure, Full stack, ATOM, Angular, bilingual Korean

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

- Microsoft Azure 900
- Registered Respiratory Therapist

REFERENCES

References available upon request